CHRIS TAEYOUNG KIM

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

christaeyoung.kim@gmail.com

647-268-0246

linkedin.com/in/chris-ty-kim/

github.com/chriskimty

chriskim.dev

PROFILE

Front-end developer passionate about creating clean, responsive and accessible web applications using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React and API Integrations, with 8+ years in the education sector, and training in the musical arts. Excellent interpersonal and communication skills, leadership, teamwork, adaptability, and ability to work under pressure. Passion for problem-solving through creativity and resourceful thinking. Lifelong learner, fitness enthusiast, and cat-mom.

EDUCATION

Juno College of Technology

- Web Development Certificate | 2022
- Web Development Course | 2022

York University

• Bachelor of Education | 2020

University of Toronto

- MA Music Education | 2017
- Honours BMus | 2016

SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS3, SCSS
- JavaScript ES6
- React.js, node.js
- RESTful APIs, Firebase
- Github, Git
- Web Accessibility
- Responsive Design
- Paired programming & team- Attention to detail based development

- Communication
- Critical Thinking
- Leadership
- Teamwork/Collaboration
- Problem Solving
- Organization (i.e. *Trello*)
- Creativity
- Project scope management

RECENT PROJECTS

Rhyme Time React | REST APIs | JS



- A single-page React app that generates rhymes per user-generated search word
- Solo project using RESTful APIs, core React concepts, understanding of app architecture, and functional programming

Queen Quotes JS | REST APIs | SCSS | HTML



- A quiz app where the user guesses which Drag Race Queen said a famous quote based on randomized data from the API
- Pair-programming project using RESTful APIs, JavaScript, DOM manipulation, error handling and UI design
- Created using vanilla JS and SCSS partials

BeachStays JS | SCSS | HTML



- A multi-page PSD conversion
- Fully responsive and accessible design
- Functional UI elements with JavaScript including a hamburger menu, form submissions and image carousel

WORK EXPERIENCE

Toronto District School Board, Teacher | Oct 2020-present

- Fostered intellectually rich and socially inclusive in-person and virtual classrooms, and reached 100+ students per semester through incorporating interactive EdTech (i.e. Nearpod, Peardeck, Flipgrid, Padlet, Mentimeter, Soundtrap etc.)
- Coordinated a year-end Music and Arts Concert which reached a 300+ community audience, and raised OSSLT scores from 92-98% through targeted extra-help

York University, Research Assistant | May-Aug 2020

• Assisted in creating a resource guide for digital music technology aimed to help classroom music teachers increase use of emerging music technologies in their classroom. Successfully implemented resource guide to support the 50+ teaching staff at the Community Music Schools of Toronto.

Helen Ziegler & Assoc., Recruitment Coordinator | May 2017-Aug 2018

- Supported in recruiting and screening healthcare candidates for hospitals in the Arabian Peninsula, and tracked the status of candidate requirements for 50+ candidates at a time
- Received a promotion from Recruitment Assistant to Recruitment Coordinator, and 2 pay raises in under 12 months

Community Music Schools of Toronto, Faculty | Jan 2017-present

- Taught music through online platforms during COVID-19 restrictions (Zoom, creating YouTube videos and using Music EdTech), reaching a total student body of 700+ students in Regent Park, Jane and Finch, and other satellite locations
- Worked with K-12 students in a classroom-setting, urban community school and developed creative resources to meet student interests and learning needs, collaborating with 50+ staff and faculty members